Guide to the Harold Saunders papers, 1976-2014
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections Research Center
Harold Saunders papers
1976-2014
C0259
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections Research Center.
15.0 linear feet (40 boxes)
Collection consists largely of speeches, meeting transcripts, peace conference documents, news clippings about Saunders, photographs, and approximately 150 pocket notebooks that he carried with him that include insights from conversations and other experiences that were important to him.
Saunders, Harold H.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Donated by Harold Saunders in 2015.
Biographical Information
Harold Henry "Hal" Saunders, born in Philadelphia, PA, was founder and Chairman of the International Institute for Sustained Dialogue (IISD) and Director of International Affairs at the Kettering Foundation. For twenty years he worked at the National Security Council (NSC) Staff in the White House (1961 - 1974) and the State Department (1974 - 1981), serving as the Assistant Secretary of State for Intelligence and Research (1975 - 1978) and Assistant Secretary of State for Near East Affairs (1978 - 1981.) Saunders was at the center of U.S. policy making in the Middle East and South Asia, and played major roles in the Camp David Accords and the Iran Hostage Crisis. After leaving his government career in 1981, he developed and practiced the process of Sustained Dialogue, a "public peace process" to transform racial and ethnic conflicts. Saunders was a graduate of both Princeton and Yale Universities, and was a veteran of the United States Air Force. Saunders passed away in 2016.
Scope and Content
The Harold Saunders papers consists largely of speeches, meeting transcripts, news clippings, photographs, and approximately 150 pocket notebooks that he carried with him that include insights from conversations and other experiences that were important to him. The most unique document is a declassified copy of the key pages of a memo he co-authored with his close colleague Ambassador Alfred LeRoy "Roy" Atherton for Secretary of State Cyrus Vance to send to President Jimmy Carter to begin his preparatory reading for the summit with Egyptian President Sadat and Israeli Prime Minister Menachem being held at Camp David in September 1978.
The most revealing sections are those focused on how Carter might have proceeded in bringing Sadat and begin the human dialogue planned for Camp David. There are also professional files including speeches and congressional testimony from 1976 to 1983, materials on the Iran Hostage Crisis in 1979, chapters for an unpublished book on presidential decision-making toward the Middle East, and speeches from 1974-1983. The collection also includes substantial documentation of international meetings, such as 37 analytical memos written after each meeting of the Inter-Tajik Dialogue (1993-2005) which was conducted by three Russian and three American members of the Dartmouth Conference Task Force on Regional Conflicts. Documentation on other meetings include records of twelve meetings over five years of a sustained dialogue involving participants from Armenia, Azerbaijan, and Nagorno-Karabakh. This includes records of what was called the Arab-American-European Dialogue, which included five senior Americans government officials, five senior European government officials, and a dozen political reformers from the Arab Islamic heartland (Lebanon, Syria, Jordan, Palestine, Iraq, and Egypt). The question of Western democracy and Islam's compatibility was the main focus during this dialogue. Also included are records of a dialogue among Iraqis across the political spectrum on national reconciliation, as well as near verbatim transcripts of meetings of the Dartmouth Conference Regional Conflicts Task Force and - its successor since 2008 - the Task Force on the Russian-U.S. Relationship which began in 1982.
Series 1: Government Career (1930s - 1985) documents Saunders' government career during the 1970s and 1980s, which includes speeches, memoranda, photos, newspaper clippings, and other documents from his tenure on the National Security Council and as a high-ranking official in the White House during multiple presidential administrations. Topics range from the Camp David Accords, the Iran Hostage Crisis, to Saunders thoughts, opinions, experiences, and actions as an American diplomat.
Series 2: Dartmouth Conference, Peace Dialogues, and Post-Government Career (1970s - 2014) documents Saunders involvement in numerous peace dialogues and experiences after his government career, and is divided into four subseries. Subseries 2.1: Dartmouth Conference, which includes multiple documents on the annual peace dialogue conference. Subseries 2.2: Peace Dialogues - Tajikistan, which includes multiple documents on Saunders involvement in the Inter-Tajik Dialogues. Subseries 2.3: Peace Dialogues - Other, which includes documents on Saunders involvement in other peace dialogues, most notably on the Middle East. Subseries 2.4: Post-Government Career Work, includes documents and reflections from Saunders on his work after his career in government.
Series 3: Notebooks, Media, and Miscellaneous (1970s - 2000) includes multiple notebooks and recordings on cassette tape on experiences during and after his career in government. Most notable are his plethora of notebooks created during and after both the Camp David Accords and the Iran Hostage Crisis.
Arrangement
Series 1: Government Career, 1930s - 1986 (Boxes 1 - 8)
Series 2: Dartmouth Conference, Peace Dialogues, and Post-Government Career, 1970s - 2014 (Boxes 8 - 30)
Series 3: Notebooks, Media, and Miscellaneous, 1970s - 2000 (Boxes 30 - 40)
Related Material
Special Collections Research Center holds several other notable collections on conflict analysis and resolution including the ,the, and the. The archives also holds Harold Saunders Material.
Alternate Format Available
Digital versions are available from box 4, folders 1-23, and Box 5, folders 1-14, 16-19, 21-24, and 27-28.
Index Terms
Persons:
Carter, Jimmy, 1924-; Kissinger, Henry, 1923-; Nixon, Richard M. (Richard Milhous), 1913-1994; Saunders, Harold H.
Geographical Names:
Camp David (Md.); Iran.; Iraq.; Middle East.; Nagorno-Karabakh (Azerbaijan).; Tajikistan.
Subjects:
Conflict management.; Dartmouth Conference. Dartmouth Conference task forces; Foreign policy; Iran Hostage Crisis, 1979-1981.; Islam.; Peacemaking
Contents List
- Series 1: Government Career (Boxes 1 - 8), 1930s-1986
  This series documents Saunders' extensive government career.
  - Documents on President Kennedy - Part 1, circa 1930s - 1980s (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Documents on President Kennedy - Part 2, circa 1930s - 1980s (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Military Service USAF Documents and Photographs, 1956 - 1959 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Documents on President Johnson, circa 1960s (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Documents and Photographs from President Kennedy's National Security Council staff, featuring National Security Advisor George Bundy, circa 1960s (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Pres. Kennedy conversation with Golda Meir" Notes, December 27, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Documents on Walt Rostow's NSC Staff and Middle East Conflicts, 1966 - 1967 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Papers of Personal Interest to Saunders - Part 1, 1967 - 1983 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Papers of Personal Interest to Saunders - Part 2, 1967 - 1983 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Documents on Nixon's Travels Abroad with NSC Staff, 1969 - 1972 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Documents and Photos on Henry Kissinger's "Secret Trip to Beijing", 1971 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Documents on Lyndon B. Johnson's NSC Staff - Includes a Letter of Condolence to Saunders on the passing of his wife from Lady Bird Johnson, 1972 - 1973 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Photos of Secret Meeting between Henry Kissinger and Hafez Ismail in Armonte, NY, February 1973 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Documents and Photographs on Arab - Israeli War, 1973 - 1974 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Documents and Photographs on Events Leading Up to Nixon's Visit to Middle East, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Saunders' Passes to Various Countries as Member of Kissinger's Team during the Ford Administration, 1974 - 1975 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Documents and Photographs on "Second Sinai Agreement", 1974 - 1975 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - "The Saunders Document", 1975 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Documents and Photographs on Saunders' appointment to Director of the Bureau of Intelligence and Research, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Speeches, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Briefing Memoranda on "Congressional Testimony on the Palestinians", November 10, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Speeches, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Documents on President Carter, circa 1977 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Documents and Photographs on Beginning of Carter Administration, 1977 - 1978 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Copy of Memo of Camp David Preparations, 1978, 2014 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Speeches - Part 1, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Speeches - Part 2, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Speeches - Part 1, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Speeches - Part 2, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Documents and Photographs of Saunders' Swearing-In Ceremony as Assistant Secretary of State for Near Eastern and South Asian Affairs, May 1978 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Vice President's Trip to Israel, June 1978 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Camp David Documents, June 1978 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Documents on Camp David Accords, October - November 1978 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Document and Photographs on Ambassador to Egypt in the 1970s Hermann Eitts, 1978 - 1979 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Article on Saunders' Peace Negotiating, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Egyptian/Israeli Peace Treaty Documents, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Speeches - Part 1, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Speeches - Part 2, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Documents and Photographs of Saunders' Award for Civilian Public Servants, April 1979 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper Article on Bob Strauss, Carter-Era Peace Negotiator, August 26, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Documents on Saunders' Involvement in the Iran Hostage Crisis, 1979 - 1980 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Documents on Arrival of the Shah of Iran, 1979 - 1980 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Speeches, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Saunders' Personal Papers on the Iran Hostage Crisis - Part 1, 1979 - 1981 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Saunders' Personal Papers on the Iran Hostage Crisis - Part 2, 1979 - 1981 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Saunders' Personal Papers on the Iran Hostage Crisis - Part 3, 1979 - 1981 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - The Challenge to American Diplomacy in the Middle East by Saunders, circa 1981 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Documents on the End of Saunders' Career, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Saunders' Professional Appointment Book, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Algiers Accords on Iran, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Documents on Algiers and Iran Hostage Crisis, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Saunders' Talks on Hostage Crisis and Supporting Materials, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Saunders' Press Interview - Numerous due to Saunders Leaving Government Career and Able to Speak Freely, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Saunders' Press Interview - Numerous due to Saunders Leaving Government Career and Able to Speak Freely - Part 2, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Speeches - Part 1 - Audio Cassette Tapes in Box 39, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Speeches - Part 2, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Speeches - Part 3, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Speeches - Negotiation - Part 1, 1981 - 1982 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Speeches - Negotiation - Part 2, 1981 - 1982 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Saunders' Post-Government Career Documents, 1981, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Iran Hostage Crisis - Congressional Testimony, February 1981 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Saunders' Professional Appointment Book and Girl Scout Pocket Planner, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Speeches - Middle East - Part 1, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Speeches - Middle East - Part 2, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Speeches - Middle East - Part 3, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - New York Times Magazine Issues on Iran Hostage Crisis, 1981, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Saunders' Professional Appointment Book and Monthly Minder, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Speeches - New Directions, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Truman Papers, December 14, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Papers on President Eisenhower - Part 1, circa 1984 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Saunders' Professional Appointment Book and "Slim Jim Pocket Pal", 1984 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Papers on President Eisenhower - Part 2, April 6, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Documents on President Ford - Includes 2 Tapes of an Interview with Ford - Housed in Box 39, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Saunders' Weekly - Minder Appointment Book, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Series 2: Dartmouth Conference, Peace Dialogues, and Post-Government Career (Boxes 8 - 30), 1970s-2014
  This series documents Saunders involvement in numerous peace dialogues and experiences after his government career.
- Subseries 2.1: Dartmouth Conference, 1970s-2014
- Documents on Dartmouth Conferences, circa 1970s, 2014 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Dartmouth Conference Documents, 1980 - 1981 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Dartmouth Conference Documents, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Documents on Dartmouth Regional Conflicts Task Force, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Documents on Dartmouth Regional Conflicts Task Force, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Documents on Dartmouth Regional Conflicts Task Force, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Documents on Dartmouth Conference Task Force, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Documents on Dartmouth Conference Task Force, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Dartmouth Conference Task Forces Document, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Dartmouth Conference Task Forces Documents, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Dartmouth Conference Task Forces Documents, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Dartmouth Working Notes, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Conceptual Agenda for Dartmouth XV (Baku), January 1984 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Dartmouth Conference Task Forces Documents, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Task Force on Southern Africa Documents, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Dartmouth Conference Documents, 1985, 2006 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Dartmouth Conference XV Documents, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Dartmouth Conference XV Documents, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- The Dartmouth Conference - 1986 Task Force Meetings - Executive Summaries (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Dartmouth Conference Regional Conflicts Task Force Documents, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Task Force on Southern Africa Documents, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Dartmouth Conference Task Forces Documents, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Dartmouth Conference Task Forces Document, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Dartmouth Conference Documents, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Substantive Agenda for Dartmouth XVI, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Papers in Preparation For Dartmouth TF, December 1988 (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Dartmouth Conference XVI Booklet, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Dartmouth Conference XVI, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Dartmouth Conference Task Force on Regional Conflicts Settlement and Prevention Stenographic Record, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Peace Task Force Documents, 1988 - 1989 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Dartmouth Conference Task Force on Regional Conflict Settlement and Prevention Stenographic Record, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Dartmouth Conference XVII Documents, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Dartmouth Conference Task Force on Regional Conflict Settlement and Prevention, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Dartmouth Conference Task Force on Regional Conflict Settlement and Prevention, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Dartmouth Conference Task Force on Regional Conflict Prevention and Resolution, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Dartmouth Conference Task Force on Regional Conflict Prevention and Resolution, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Dartmouth Conference Task Force on Regional Conflict Prevention and Resolution, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Dartmouth Regional Conflicts Task Force Documents, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Dartmouth Conference Task Forces Documents, 1991 - 1992 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Documents on Middle-East and Asian Countries, 1992-1993 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Dartmouth Conference Task Force Documents, 1992 - 1994 (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Dartmouth Conference Task Force on Regional Conflict Prevention and Resolution, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Dartmouth Conference Regional Task Force Documents, May - June 1993 (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Briefing Papers for Peace Task Force, 1993 - 1994 (Box 12, Folder 10)
- Dartmouth Regional Conflicts Task Force Documents, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 11)
- Dartmouth Conference Task Forces - Georgian Conflict in the Context of Russian-American Relations, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 12)
- Russian-American Relations and the Challenges to a New Partnership, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 13)
- Dartmouth Conference Regional Conflicts Task Force Documents, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 14)
- Documents on Politics of Eastern Europe, 1996 - 1997 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Dartmouth Conference Regional Conflicts Task Force, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Documents and Ephemera from the Dartmouth Conference Reunion - Part 1, 2000, 2010 (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Documents from the Dartmouth Conference Reunion - Part 2, 2000, 2010 (Box 13, Folder 4)
- First Round - Seminar on Nagorno - Karabakh, 2001 (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Round Two - Discussions on Nagorno - Karabakh, 2002 (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Dartmouth Conference Documents, 2002 (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Dartmouth Conference Documents, 2002 (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Dartmouth Conference on Nagorny - Karabakh Documents, 2003 (Box 13, Folder 9)
- Dartmouth Conference on Nagorny - Karabakh Documents, 2003 (Box 13, Folder 10)
- Dartmouth Conference on Nagorny - Karabakh, 2004 (Box 13, Folder 11)
- Dartmouth Conference on Nagorny - Karabakh, 2004 (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Dartmouth Conference on Nagorno - Karabakh, 2004 (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Dartmouth Conference on Nagorny - Karabakh Documents, 2005 (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Dartmouth conference on Nagorny - Karabakh, 2005 (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Dartmouth Conference on Nagorno - Karabakh Documents, 2006 (Box 14, Folder 5)
- Dartmouth Conference on Nagorno - Karabakh Documents, 2006 (Box 14, Folder 6)
- Documents on Nagorno - Karabakh, 2007 (Box 14, Folder 7)
- Documents on Nagorno - Karabakh and Helsinki, 2007 (Box 14, Folder 8)
- Nagorno - Karabakh Dialogue Email Correspondence, 2007 (Box 14, Folder 9)
- Dialogue on Nagorno - Karabakh, 2007 (Box 14, Folder 10)
- Dartmouth Conference Meeting Documents, 2008 (Box 14, Folder 11)
- Documents on U.S. - Russian Relations, 2008 (Box 14, Folder 12)
- Dartmouth Conference/Russia Documents, 2008 - 2009 (Box 14, Folder 13)
- Russia and Helsinki Documents, 2008 - 2010 (Box 14, Folder 14)
- Dartmouth RCTF Documents, 2009 (Box 14, Folder 15)
- Repairing U.S. - Russian Relations: A Long Road Ahead by Eugene B. Rumer and Angela E. Stent, April 2009 (Box 14, Folder 16)
- Dartmouth Conference Documents, 2009 (Box 15, Folder 1)
- Documents on Paris and Helsinki, 2009 (Box 15, Folder 2)
- Dartmouth Conference Documents, 2009 (Box 15, Folder 3)
- Documents on Russia, 2009 (Box 15, Folder 4)
- Documents on NATO and Russia, 2009 (Box 15, Folder 5)
- Dartmouth Conference Ephemera - 50th Anniversary, October 2010 (Box 15, Folder 6)
- Dartmouth Conference Documents, 2010 (Box 15, Folder 7)
- U.S. - Russian Relations Document, 2010 (Box 15, Folder 8)
- Dartmouth Conference Documents, 2011 (Box 15, Folder 9)
- Dartmouth Conference Documents, 2011 (Box 15, Folder 10)
- Dartmouth Conference and Russia Documents, 2011 (Box 15, Folder 11)
- Russian Civil Society: Talking About Partnership and Cooperation with the United States, 2011 - 2012 (Box 15, Folder 12)
- Russian Civil Society is Holding out by Boris Pustyntsev, circa 2012 (Box 15, Folder 13)
- Report - Expansion of Public Deliberation in Russia: Opportunities and Threat, 2012 (Box 15, Folder 14)
- Dartmouth Conference and U.S. - Russian Relations Documents, 2012 (Box 15, Folder 15)
- Dartmouth Conference and U.S. - Russian Relations Documents, 2012 (Box 15, Folder 16)
- Saunders' Email Correspondence on Dartmouth Conference, 2012 (Box 15, Folder 17)
- Dartmouth Conference and U.S. - Russian Relations Documents - Part 1, 2013 (Box 15, Folder 18)
- Dartmouth Conference and U.S. - Russian Relations Documents - Part 2, 2013 (Box 15, Folder 19)
- Dartmouth Conference Notebook - "Regional Task Force - Political Relations Task Force", May, November, December 1986 (Box 16, Folder 1)
- Dartmouth Conference Notebook - "Task Forces", 1987 - 1988 (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Dartmouth Conference Notebook - "Brown University and Wingspread Conferences, Regional Conference Task Force", July, December 1988 - 1989 (Box 16, Folder 3)
- Dartmouth Conference Notebook - "RCTF", 1989 - 1990 (Box 16, Folder 4)
- Dartmouth Conference Notebook - "Task Forces", 1991 - 1992 (Box 16, Folder 5)
- Dartmouth Conference Notebook - "Task Forces", 1992 - 1993 (Box 16, Folder 6)
- Dartmouth Conference Notebook - "Tajik #2 - 4", 1993 (Box 16, Folder 7)
- Dartmouth Conference Notebook, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 8)
- Dartmouth Conference Notebook - "Tajik 8 - 10, RCTF", June - December 1994 (Box 16, Folder 9)
- Dartmouth Conference Notebook - "Tajik 11 - 14", March - November 1995 (Box 16, Folder 19)
- Dartmouth Conference Notebook - "RCTF", September 1995 - October 1997 (Box 16, Folder 11)
- Dartmouth Conference Notebook - "Civil Soc. Dialogue", 1996 (Box 16, Folder 12)
- Dartmouth Conference Notebook - "Tajik 15 - 19", 1996 - 1997 (Box 16, Folder 13)
- Dartmouth Conference Notebook - "Tajik 20 - 23", October 1997 - 1998 (Box 16, Folder 14)
- Dartmouth Conference Notebook - "Tajik #24 - 27", 1999 - 2000 (Box 16, Folder 15)
- Dartmouth Conference Notebook - "RCTF", 1998 - 2001 (Box 16, Folder 16)
- Dartmouth Conference Notebook - "Dartmouth Reunion" - Papers from Notebook in Folder, 2000 (Box 16, Folder 17)
- Dartmouth Conference Notebook - "#28 - 32", 2000 - 2001 (Box 16, Folder 18)
- Dartmouth Conference Notebook, 2002 - 2003 (Box 17, Folder 1)
- Dartmouth Conference Notebook - "Tajik #33 - 36", 2002 - 2003 (Box 17, Folder 2)
- Dartmouth Conference Notebook - "Tajik regional dial. Mods", 2004 (Box 17, Folder 3)
- Dartmouth Conference Notebook - "A-E-A #1 -3", 2004 - 2005 (Box 17, Folder 4)
- Dartmouth Conference Notebook - "AANK", 2004 - 2007 (Box 17, Folder 5)
- Dartmouth Conference Notebook - "#4 - 5, A-A-E including Iraq", 2005 (Box 17, Folder 6)
- Dartmouth Conference Notebook - "AAE, 2005 - 2007 (Box 17, Folder 7)
- Dartmouth Conference Notebook - "Tajik", 2006 - 2007 (Box 17, Folder 8)
- Dartmouth Conference Notebook - "Iraq #2", 2007 (Box 17, Folder 9)
- Dartmouth Conference Notebook - "Iraq 1 - 4", 2007 - 2008 (Box 17, Folder 10)
- Dartmouth Conference Notebook, 2008 - 2010 (Box 17, Folder 11)
- Subseries 2.2: Peace Dialogues - Tajikistan, 1987-2009
- Background Papers on Tajikistan, 1987 - 1997 (Box 18, Folder 1)
- Saunders/Tajikistan Correspondence, circa 1990 (Box 18, Folder 2)
- Discussion Draft - Framework for an NGO Strategy Toward Tajikistan, circa 1990 (Box 18, Folder 3)
- Working Glossary of People and Places in Tajikistan, circa 1992 (Box 18, Folder 4)
- Tajik Dialogue Documents, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 5)
- Russian Centre for Strategic Research and International Studies - The Fourth Dialogue on Tajikistan, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 6)
- Tajikistan Dialogue #2 Document, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 7)
- Tajikistan Dialogue #3 Document, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 8)
- Tajikistan Dialogue #4 Documents, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 9)
- Tajikistan Dialogue Documents, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 10)
- American Embassy in Duhanbe, Tajikistan "Phone List of Important Contacts", February 25, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 11)
- Tajik Dialogue - Moscow, March 23-24, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 12)
- Tajikistan Dialogue Document, May 21, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 13)
- CSIS - Meeting on "Tadjikistan", June 9, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 14)
- The Third Tajik Dialogue, August 1 - 3, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 15)